CHARITY MAE MANLANGIT

Antipas, North Cotabato, Philippines ● charitymanlangit@gmail.com ● (63) 917-301-2414 https://www.linkedin.com/in/charity-mae-manlangit-9a976b18b/

General Virtual Assistant • Nursing Assistant • Entrepreneur

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am a self-motivated virtual assistant who helps and has the knowledge to assist the needs of the client. Outstanding and excellent, with great communicating skills, accomplished day to day activities preparing all legal documents for filing, supervised and coordinated word processing requests, dynamic and goal-driven executive and achieving business objectives and revenue growth, responsible for negotiating, researching and coding related to various researched information. You can count on me to be part of your team.

CORE COMPETENCIES		
Data Entry	 Computer Network Specialist 	 Researching and
Word Processors	 Customer service Representative 	coding
Clerical Assistance	Installed and manage data network	
 Execute and achieving objectives 	 Multi-tasking and adaptability 	

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Word Processors and Typist, Network and Computer Systems Administrators, Buzzy Hands Computer Lounge Internet Cafe ◆ Antipas, North Cotabato

April 2014 - Present

- Creating documents from scratch, handwritten documents, and typed copy template by the clients.
- Use word processing software to create business documents, spreadsheets and presentations.
- Accurate and timely data entry with multiple area of office services.
- Multi-tasked and completed other related duties of the client.
- Printing documents and Photos.

Patient Care Assistant, *Ministry of Health, Markaz Taheel Dammam Comprehensive Rehabilitation Center*♦ *Dammam, Saudi Arabia* November 2009 – September 2013

- Detailed and note all patient observation and need then report it to the physician and other health care practitioners.
- Giving care and supplying basic needs of the cerebral palsy patient such as clothing, cleaning agent and other.
- Maintained cleanliness to the establishment and area responsibility as well to our self.
- Treating in a well-mannered and have respect to the colleagues and to the patient.
- Managed and organized the work responsibility.

Housekeeper, King Fahad Specialist Hospital ♦ Dammam, Saudi Arabia

July – December 2012

- Part-time and reliever to every department when the assigned staff is day off or absent.
- Responsible for the cleanliness and have proper ways of segregating waste of the hospital.
- Prepare treatment rooms for patient examinations, keeping the rooms neat and clean.
- Make sure have enough knowledge in using chemicals for cleaning.

Sales Representative, Global Manpower Inc. ♦ J.P. Laurel Ave. Davao City

May – July 2008

- Team oriented and willing to lead and work with colleagues to achieve goals and expectations
- Skilled in making sales presentations to customers and to convince them about the product
- On time to report in office to present the documentation
- Consistently meeting sales quotas.

CERTIFICATES AND TRAINING

112 Hour Virtual Assistance Training ♦ Quickdesk Virtual Solutions ♦ Tres de Mayo Digos City

- July 2019 October 2019
- Introduction to Computers, Word Processing, & Google Suite
- Photo Editing using Adobe Photoshop
- Social Media Marketing & Management
- Search Engine Optimization
- Video Editing for FB Ads and E-commerce
- Audio Editing
- WIX Web Designing
- WordPress Web Designing
- Email Marketing
- Administrative Assistance
- Lead Generation & Product Sourcing
- Resume, Linkedin Profile, and Cover Letter Writing Skills
- Communication Skills

Health Care Service Training NCII ◆ TESDA (Technical Education and Skills Development

Authority) ♦ Kidapawan City, Philippines

February 2009

Maintain Patient Services, Prepare and Maintain Beds, Assist Patient in Mobility and Transporting, Handle Waste in a Health Care Environment, Health and Safety Procedure, Implement and Monitor Infection Control, Apply Basic First Aid

Nursing Assistant Training ◆Davao Medical Center ◆ J. P. Laurel Avenue, Bajada, Davao City, Philippines

July-November 2008

NICU Department (Nursery Intensive Care Unit)

- Monitoring vital signs provides round-the-clock care for the basic and medical needs of newborn infants.
- Providing intensive care to dangerously ill or premature newborn babies.

ER Department (Emergency Room)

• Assist doctors, assist the clinical nursing team in all aspects of nursing care, and treat patients experiencing critical injury, allergic reactions or trauma, compassionate, safe and effective care.

Neuro Ward

- Assist neurological doctors and clinical nursing team, and inform them about patient's conditions.
- Monitoring vital signs of the patients, assist patient in pre-operative and post-operative care.

Gyne Ward

- Take vital signs, make sure patients are comfortable and assist the nursing staff when requested.
- Manage mothers and newborns through clinical and nursing care services.
- Coordinate with other nurses and clinical staff in treating newborns and mothers.

Hospital Waste Management Program ◆ *Davao Medical Center* **◆** J. P. Laurel Avenue, Bajada, Davao City, Philippines

October 2008

Provides practical information regarding safe, efficient, and environment-friendly waste management. It contains in detail, safety procedure attendant to the collection, handling, storage, transport, treatment and disposal of health care waste.

Leadership Training ◆ Red Cross Philippines ◆ Kidapawan City, Philippines

December 2007

Prepare in becoming full-fledged members through assessing ones strengths and weaknesses, clarify and re-assesses their values and integrating corporate values to further increase leadership ideals. The training which involves physical activities, their leadership skills and talents were enhanced.

EDUCATION

Virtual Assistance ◆ Quickdesk Virtual Solutions **◆** *Tres de Mayo Digos City* October 2019

Nursing Aide Specialized in Caregiving ◆ RDACC (Read Data Access Computer College) Kidapawan City, Philippines 2008

Bachelor of Science in Nursing ◆ CDK (Colegio de Kidapawan) Kidapawan City, Philippines 2005–2006

INTERPERSONAL SKILLS/COMPUTER SKILLS/TECHNICAL SKILLS

Empathy, Leadership, Active Listening, Negotiation, Teamwork, Costumer Service, Creative Thinking, Observe and record vital signs, including respiration, body temperature, pulse, and blood pressure, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint, Administrative Assistance, Web Designing, Video Editing, Photo Editing, Social Media Management, Social Media Marketing, Email Marketing, Email Management, Project Management, Customer Support, Blogging/Article Writing, Graphic Design, Search Engine Optimization (Off-Page/On-Page), Newsletter Design/Content Creation, Word Processing, Spreadsheet, Lead Generation